www.tvsubtitles.net
The wolf pup has gone south.
The North is ripe for
the taking.
You'll take a ship to raid the
fishing villages on the Stony Shore
- I'm to fight fishermen?
- Be careful of their nets.
- Lovely boy.
- What do you want?
You're called Arry?
A boy could make a friend.
This man has the honor
to be Jaqen H'ghar.
Every night it's the same.
I'm running through
the Godswood howling.
These are dreams,
nothing more.
My dreams are different.
Mine are true.
I saw something take that child.
Wildlings serve crueler
Gods than you or I.
Ready my horse.
We leave at dawn.
Did Cersei have you
knighted before or after
she took you into her bed?
- Nothing to say?
- Mercy! Mercy, My Lord!
I want to know what Cersei is
doing and you will tell me.
Yes, My Lord, I will.
Sweet boy!
Help us!
Round up any survivors.
We'll take them
back to Harrenhal.
This one's a girl
dressed as a boy.
Get these prisoners to work.
Bring the girl.
I need a new cupbearer.
I will give you this
one night to reconsider.
Otherwise I shall
destroy you.
Look to your sins,
Lord Renly.
The night is dark
and full of terrors.
I will vouch for her,
her people and her dragons.
Be it on your head.
Welcome to Qarth, My Lady.
Trust you've not forgotten
your smuggler's tricks.
- What am I bringing ashore?
- The red woman.
No one must know what you do
and we'll not speak of this again.
♪ Game of Thrones 2x05 ♪
The Ghost of Harrenhal
Original Air Date on April 29, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
- You swear it?
- By the mother.
My son has no interest
in the Iron Throne.
Then I see no reason
for hostility between us.
Your son can go on calling
himself King in the North,
the Starks will have dominion over
all lands north of Moat Cailin,
provided he swears me
an oath of fealty.
And the wording
of this oath?
The same Ned Stark swore
to Robert 18 years ago.
Cat, their friendship held
the kingdoms together.
And in return
for my son's loyalty?
In the morning I'll destroy
my brother's army.
When that's done,
Baratheon and Stark
will fight
their common enemy
together,
as they have done
many times before.
Our two houses
have always been close,
which is why I am begging you
to reconsider this battle.
Negotiate a peace
with your brother.
Negotiate with Stannis?
You heard him out there.
I'd have better luck
debating the wind.
Please bring my terms
to your son.
I believe we are
natural allies.
I hope he feels
the same.
Together we could end
this war in a fortnight.
No!
- No.
- Follow me!
- You'll die for this.
- No, wait, it wasn't her!
- You'll-.
- No, wa-
We've got to leave.
They'll hang you
for this.
- Inside the King's tent, go!
- Now!
I won't leave him.
You can't avenge him
if you're dead.
Over there, go!
Not that way.
We need to go home.
- Loras.
- My Lord, My Lady.
Get out.
Stannis will be here
in an hour.
When he arrives, Renly's
bannermen will flock to him.
Your former companions
will fight for the privilege
of selling you
to their new king.
And you want that
privilege for yourself.
You will note that I am
standing here talking to you,
- not Stannis.
- There's no time for this.
Ride back to
Highgarden, sister.
I'm not running
from Stannis.
Brienne of Tarth
murdered Renly.
I don't believe that.
You don't believe that.
Who gained the most
from our king's death?
Stannis.
I will put a sword
through his righteous face.
You can't stay here.
He would have been
a true king,
a good king.
Tell me, Ser Loras,
what do you desire
most in this world?
Revenge.
I have always found that to
be the purest of motivations,
but you won't have a chance to
put your sword through Stannis,
not today.
You'll be cut to pieces before
he sets foot on solid ground.
If it is justice
that you want,
be smart about it.
You can't avenge him
from the grave.
Bring the horses.
Please.
He was very handsome.
He was, Your Grace.
"Your Grace."
Calling yourself king
doesn't make you one.
And if Renly wasn't a king,
I wasn't a queen.
Do you want to be a queen?
No.
I want to be the queen.
Killed?
By whom?
Accounts differ.
Most seem to implicate
Catelyn Stark in some way.
Really?
Who'd have thought?
Some say it was one
of his own Kingsguard,
while still others say it was
Stannis himself who did it
after negotiations
went sour.
Whomever did it,
I say well done.
It's not what Varys says.
He says Renly's army is
flocking to support Stannis,
which would give Stannis superiority
over us on both land and sea.
Littlefinger says we can
outspend him three to one.
And I say father raised you to
have too much respect for money.
Stannis Baratheon
is coming for us,
sooner rather than later.
Aren't there other things
you should be doing,
like sealing my daughter in a crate
so you can ship her away?
She'll be safer in Dorne.
Yes, I know how concerned
you are for her safety.
It so happens that I am.
Myrcella is a sweet,
innocent girl
and I don't blame her
at all for you.
So clever.
Aren't you
always so clever
with your schemes
and your plots?
Schemes and plots
are the same thing.
They are going
to attack us.
We need to be ready.
No need to concern
yourself over it.
The King is taking personal
charge of siege preparations.
May I ask specifically
what the King has in mind?
You may specifically
or you may ask vaguely.
The answer will be
the same.
It's important
that we talk about this.
It's the King's
royal prerogative
to withhold sensitive information
from his councilors.
It's wildfire.
Wildfire?
You wouldn't lie to me,
would you, cousin?
- No.
- That's a lie right there.
It is not a lie.
Why would I lie?
Tell me,
if the vile allegations
against my brother
and sister are true,
do you think it will
make Jaime more likely
to kill you or less likely?
When I tell him
you're fucking her, I mean.
I'm telling you the truth.
The smart money
would be on more likely.
She's making wildfire.
But then perhaps his own unnatural
urges will give him sympathy for yours.
The alchemists' guild
is being commissioned.
I suppose there's only
one way to find out.
They have thousands of pots
already stored in their vaults.
They are planning to launch
them from the city walls
into Stannis's ships
and armies.
Please.
When did she
tell you this?
I heard her talking
with the Pyromancer.
And the other night
after I left her,
she went to meet him.
- I swear to you.
- Swear to me on what?
- On my life.
- But I don't care about your life.
In the Light of the Seven,
by all that is
holy and right,
I, Lancel Lannister,
do solemnly vow--
All right, all right.
Enough.
Even torturing
you is boring.
Just get out.
Oh, Lancel,
tell my friend Bronn
to please kill you if anything
should happen to me.
Please kill me if anything
should happen to Lord Tyrion.
It will be my pleasure.
- Your Grace.
- What is it?
Your Grace.
I'm sorry about
your brother, Your Grace.
I wanted to let you know
that people grieve for him.
Your Grace.
- Fools love a fool.
- Your Grace.
I grieve for him as well--
for the boy he was,
not the man
he grew to be.
I need to speak to you about
what I saw in that cave.
I thought I made it clear
to you there'd be no need to
speak to me on this matter.
Your Grace, I--
I've never known you to
need to hear a thing twice.
And I've never known you
to hide from the truth.
You've come to lecture
me on truth?
I've come to tell you
that what I saw--
All my brother's bannermen
have come to my side.
Except the Tyrells,
who fled like cowards.
They won't be able
to resist us now.
Soon I shall be sitting
on the Iron Throne.
Nothing is worth
what this will cost you,
- not even the Iron--
- I'll hear no more about it.
Take a company of men,
secure the perimeter.
When do we sail
for King's Landing?
As soon as I've
consolidated my troops.
We'll make short work
of the Lannisters' fleet.
Once Blackwater Bay
is cleared,
we'll deliver our troops to their
doorstep and take the city.
And will you bring
Lady Melisandre with you?
That's not your concern.
If you take King's Landing with her
by your side, the victory will be hers.
I never thought I'd have reason to
doubt your loyalty. Was I wrong?
Loyal service means
telling hard truths.
Oh, truth again.
All right,
what's the truth?
The hard truth?
She's a foreigner
preaching her
foreign religion.
Some believe she whispers orders
in your ear and you obey.
What do you believe?
You won those bannermen
from Renly.
Don't lose them to her.
We set out for King's Landing
without Lady Melisandre.
And you lead the fleet
into Blackwater Bay.
Your Grace, I'm honored,
but my time on the sea
was spent evading ships,
not attacking them.
The other lords
won't be happy.
Most of those lords should
consider themselves lucky
I don't hang them
for treason.
Hard truths cut
both ways, Ser Davos.
I've got it!
So it's that one there
at the top, on the right.
Buy my fruit, My Lord.
Fresh fruit.
Stannis has more infantry,
more ships, more horses.
What do we have?
There's that mind of yours
you keep going on about.
Well, I've never actually been
able to kill people with it.
Good thing.
I'd be out of a job.
What about your father?
He hasn't sent
a raven in weeks.
He's very busy.
Being repeatedly humiliated by
Robb Stark is time-consuming.
We won't be able to hold
the city against Stannis,
not the way Joffrey's
planning on holding it.
Corruption, yes.
We are swollen,
bloated, foul.
Brother fornicates with sister
in the bed of Kings
and we're surprised when the
fruit of their incest is rotten?
Yes, a rotten king.
It's hard to argue
with his assessment.
Not after what he did
to your birthday present.
The King is a lost cause.
It's the rest of us
I'm worried about now.
A dancing king, prancing
down his bloodstained halls
to the tune of a twisted
demon monkey.
You have to admire
his imagination.
- He's talking about you.
- What?
Demon monkey?
People think you're pulling
the King's strings.
They blame you
for the city's ills.
Blame me?
I'm trying to save them.
You don't need
to convince me.
Demon monkey.
( Seagulls screeching
Yeah, come on.
You're the crew
of the sea bitch?
I'm your commander.
Welcome.
Stop.
Stop!
Your Captain commands
you to stop.
Where are we
heading, Captain?
The Stony Shore
to raid their villages.
There'll be spoils
in it for you, and women,
if you do your jobs well.
And who decides if we've
done our jobs well?
I do.
Your Captain.
I have been reaving
and raping
since before you left
Balon's balls, Captain.
Don't reckon I've got much use
for your ideas on how to do it.
Don't reckon I've got
much use for a captain at all.
I'm thinking I can do the job
of captain real well myself.
All I need is a ship.
You wouldn't know
where I could find myself
a ship now, would you?
You could do that,
take the ship,
head out on your own.
And I will hunt you down,
drag you back here in chains,
and hang you for a traitor.
Stop. We yield.
Congratulations
on your first command.
Thank you. Kind of you
to come see me off.
Oh, I'm not here
for you.
I was just on my way
to Red Harbor.
I've got 30 ships. There's
nowhere to put them here.
- Too narrow.
- You'd better get out there.
Wouldn't want them
to set sail without you.
That would never happen.
My crew would wait on deck
for a year if I asked them to.
This lot, though...
Enjoy the Stony Shore.
Come on,
I'll take you out.
Who are you?
Dagmer, your first mate.
Why aren't you with
the rest of them?
Or did they send you to row me
out and dump me halfway in the sea?
That would be good
for a laugh.
They're not gonna respect you
until you prove yourself.
And how am I supposed
to prove myself by pillaging
piss-poor fishing villages?
You're not.
And yet that's the task
my father has given me
to prove that
I'm a true Iron Islander.
They're all Iron Islanders.
Do they do as they're told
or do they do as they like?
The Stony Shore's not far
from Torrhen's Square.
The seat of the House
of Tallhart--
a more impressive prize than
a few fishermen's daughters.
What, you don't think
we could take it?
No, we could.
We could never hold it
for more than a few days.
As soon as Winterfell got word that
we'd taken Torrhen's Square,
the Starks would send
their men to take it back.
And then--
take me to my ship.
The Starks have
overextended their lines.
Now that summer's over,
they'll have a hard time
keeping their men
and horses fed.
The Starks understand winter
better than we ever will.
The cold won't beat them.
Our spies report growing
discontent among the northern lords.
They want to return home
and gather the harvest
before the crops turn.
And I'm sure if those same spies
snuck into our own encampments,
they would report growing discontent
amongst the southern lords.
This is war;
No one's content.
We've underestimated
the Stark boy for too long.
He has a good mind for warfare,
his men worship him.
And as long as he keeps
winning battles,
they'll keep believing
he is King in the North.
You've been waiting
for him to fail.
He is not going to fail,
not without our help.
So how do we stop him?
We've worked through
the night, My Lord.
Perhaps we'd profit
from some sleep.
As I think
you would, Reginald.
And because
you're my cousin,
I might even let you
wake from that sleep.
Go, I'm sure your wife
must miss you.
My wife's in Lannisport.
Well, then you'd
better start riding.
Go before I change my mind
and send her your head.
If your name
wasn't Lannister,
you'd be scrubbing out pots
in the cook's tent. Go!
Not wine, water.
We'll be here
for some time.
Girl.
Where are you from?
Maidenpool, My Lord.
And who are the Lords
of Maidenpool?
- Remind me.
- House Mooton, My Lord.
And what is their Sigil?
A red salmon.
I think a Maidenpool girl
would remember that.
You're a northerner,
aren't you?
Good. One more time,
where are you from?
Barrowton, My Lord.
House Dustin.
Two crossed longaxes
beneath a black crown.
And what do they say
of Robb Stark in the North?
They call him
the young wolf.
And?
They say he rides into battle on
the back of a giant Direwolf.
They say he can turn into
a wolf himself when he wants.
They say he can't be killed.
And do you believe them?
No, My Lord.
Anyone can be killed.
Fetch that water.
A girl says nothing.
A girl keeps
her mouth closed.
No one hears,
and friends may talk
in secret, yes?
A boy becomes a girl.
I was always a girl.
And I was always aware.
But the girl
keeps secrets.
It is not for a man
to spoil them.
You're one of them now.
I should have let you burn.
And you fetch water
for one of them now.
Why is this right for you
and wrong for me?
I didn't have a choice.
You did.
I did.
And here we are.
A man pays his debts.
A man owes three.
Three what?
The Red God takes
what is his, lovely girl.
And only death
may pay for life.
You saved me
and the two I was with.
You stole three deaths
from the Red God.
We have to give them back.
Speak three names
and the man
will do the rest.
Three lives
I will give you--
no more, no less,
and we're done.
I can name anyone
and you'll kill him?
A man has said.
The one who
tortures everyone.
A man needs a name.
I don't know his name.
They call him
the Tickler.
That is enough.
Go now, girl.
Your master is thirsty.
He's not here yet.
He'd have seen us,
blown the horn.
When will he come?
The Halfhand does things
in his own time.
My uncle told me
stories about him.
Most of them are true.
I heard the Halfhand spent half
of last winter beyond the wall.
The whole winter.
He was north of the Skirling Pass
when the snows came.
Had to wait for the thaw.
So it is possible for someone
to survive out here on their own.
Well, possible
for the Halfhand.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Gilly would love it here.
There's nothing more sickening
than a man in love.
About time you did something.
At least you'll keep warm.
The fist
of the First Men.
Think of how old
this place is--
before the Targaryens
defeated the Hendals,
before the Andals took
Westeros from the First Men.
Before I die, please,
stop talking.
Thousands and thousands
of years ago,
the First Men stood here
where we're standing
all through the long night.
What do you think they
were like, the First Men?
Stupid.
Smart people don't find
themselves in places like this.
I think
they were afraid.
I think they came here
to get away from something.
And I don't think
it worked.
Wildlings?
One blast is for rangers returning.
Wildlings is two blasts.
So you got to stand
there waiting,
wondering.
One blast for friends,
two for foes.
And three
for White Walkers.
It's been 1,000 years,
but that's the only time
they blow the horn three times.
But if it's been 1,000 years,
how do you know?
- Well...
- I read it in a book.
Look.
It's Qhorin Halfhand.
Aye, we'll live
another day.
Hurrah.
Take care, My Lord.
I remember reading
an old sailor's proverb--
"piss on wildfire
and your cock burns off."
Oh, I have not conducted
this experiment.
It could well be true.
The substance
burns so hot,
it melts wood,
stone, even steel,
and, of course, flesh.
The substance burns so hot,
it melts flesh like tallow.
After the dragons died,
wildfire was the key
to the Targaryen power.
My companion takes issue.
If I could tell you
how many crazy old men
I've seen pushing carts
around army camps
making grand claims about
jars full of pig shit...
- No offense meant.
- Our order does not deal in pig shit.
The substance
is fire given form.
And we have been perfecting it
since the days of Maegor.
To do what?
The jars are put in catapults
and flung at the enemy.
How much do you have?
If you could get real soldiers
to man the catapults,
then maybe you'd hit
your target one time in 10,
but all the real soldiers are in
the Riverlands with your father.
My Lord, this man
is insulting.
I don't know if you've
ever seen a battle, old man,
but things can get
a bit messy.
'Cause when we're flinging
things at Stannis,
he's flinging them
right back at us.
Men die, men shit
themselves, men run,
which means
pots falling,
which means fire
inside the walls,
which means the poor cunts
trying to defend the city
end up burning it down.
My friend remains
unconvinced.
He would not dare
insult my order
whilst Aerys Targaryen
lived.
Well, he's not
living anymore.
And all his pots of wildfire
didn't help him, did they?
Men win wars,
not magic tricks.
We have been working
tirelessly day and night
ever since your royal sister
commanded us to do so.
Our present count stands
at 7,811,
enough to burn Stannis
Baratheon's fleet
and armies both.
This is a shit idea.
I'm afraid I have to concur
with my advisor, wisdom Hallyne.
The contents of this room
could lay King's Landing low.
You won't be making wildfire
for my sister any longer.
You'll be making it
for me.
Dracarys.
He'll be able to feed
himself from now on.
Let him sleep, Doreah.
Yes, Khaleesi.
He loves you.
Thank you, my friend.
Did you see the dress
Xaro had made for you?
They say he's the
wealthiest man in Qarth.
It is known.
And if Qarth is the wealthiest
city in Essos--
The last time a rich man
gave me a dress,
he was selling me
to Khal Drogo.
Xaro is our host,
but we know nothing about him.
Men like to talk
about other men
when they're happy.
You would look like
a real princess in Xaro's--
She's not a princess.
She's a Khaleesi.
You should wear it,
Khaleesi.
You are their guest.
It would be rude not to.
And you must visit
the night market.
The Qartheen night market is like
no night market you've ever seen.
It sounds wonderful.
The Meereens think
they have a night market.
I will take you
there myself.
Please excuse me
for a moment.
What are they doing?
Malakko says the statue
is too heavy to carry.
Kovarro says that
Malakko is an idiot.
They can pry out the gems,
the rest is pure gold.
Very soft. He can chop off
as much as we can carry.
My brother used to say the only
thing the Dothraki knew how to do
was steal things
better men have built.
It's not the only thing.
They're quite good
at killing the better men.
That's not the kind of queen
I'm going to be.
Mother of Dragons.
On behalf of the warlocks
of Qarth,
I welcome you.
A demonstration?
Take this gem.
Look at it.
Into its depths.
So many facets.
Look closely enough and you
can see yourself in them.
Often more than once.
Should you grow tired of
Xaro's baubles and trinkets,
it would be an honor to host you
at the House of the Undying.
You're always welcome,
Mother of Dragons.
My apologies.
Pyat Pree is one
of the Thirteen.
It was customary for me
to extend him an invitation.
Customs die
slow deaths in Qarth.
What is the House
of the Undying?
It is where the warlocks go
to squint at dusty books
and drink shade
of the evening.
It turns their lips blue
and their minds soft--
so soft,
they actually believe
their parlor tricks
are magic.
You watch over her.
Do I know you?
I know you.
Jorah Mormont
of Bear Island.
Who are you?
I'm no one.
But she is
the Mother of Dragons.
She needs true protectors
now more than ever.
They shall come
day and night
to see the wonder born
into the world again.
And when they see,
they shall lust,
for dragons are fire
made flesh.
And fire is power.
It looked like Stannis.
To me it just
looked like...
A shadow in
the shape of a man.
In the shape
of Stannis.
We should reach
my son's camp tomorrow.
Will you stay there
long, My Lady?
Only long enough to tell
Robb what I have seen.
After that, I will leave
for Winterfell.
My two youngest need me.
I've been away from them
for far too long.
I never knew my mother.
I'm sorry.
My own mother died
on the birthing bed
when I was very young.
It's a bloody business.
What comes after
is even harder.
Once you're safely back
amongst your own people,
will you give me leave
to go, My Lady?
You mean to kill Stannis.
I swore a vow.
But Stannis has
a great army around him.
His own guards are sworn
to keep him safe.
I'm as good
as any of them.
I should never have fled.
Renly's death
was no fault of yours.
You served him bravely.
I only held him
that once
as he was dying.
He's gone, Brienne.
You serve nothing and no one
by following him into the earth.
Renly's enemies are
Robb's enemies as well.
I do not know
your son, My Lady...
but I could serve you
if you would have me.
You have courage.
Not battle courage, perhaps,
but, I don't know,
a woman's kind of courage.
And I think that
when the time comes,
you will not hold me back.
Promise me that you
will not hold me back
from Stannis.
When the time comes,
I will not hold you back.
Then I am yours,
My Lady.
I will shield your back
and give my life for yours
if it comes to that.
I swear it by the Old Gods
and the new.
I vow that you shall always
have a place in my home
and at my table
and that I shall ask
no service of you
that might
bring you dishonor.
I swear it by the Old Gods
and the new.
And it's not
just thieves, My Lord.
There's wolves
in them hills now,
more than I've ever seen.
They come down in the night
and they kill my sheep.
My three sons is away fighting
for your brother, My Lord.
They'll fight,
keep fighting
till they're told
to go home.
I have no one to man
my flock now. Only me.
I can't keep watch
all day and all night.
We can send two orphan boys
from Winterstown home with you
to help watch over
your flock
if you can give them
room and board.
My wife always prayed
for more children.
We'll look after them.
Thank you, My Lord.
And may the Gods
bless you and yours.
Stop it.
If that's everyone, I'm going
to go for a ride before dark.
- Good.
- Hodor.
Bran-- Lord Stark.
Torrhen's Square
is under siege.
Torrhen's Square is barely
40 leagues from here.
How can the Lannisters
strike so far north?
Might be a raiding party
led by the Mountain.
Might be Sellswords
paid by Tywin Lannister.
We have to help them.
Most of the fighting men
are away with Robb,
but I can gather
200 decent men.
Do you need so many?
If we can't protect
our own bannermen,
why should
they protect us?
Go, Ser Rodrik.
Take the men you need.
Won't take long, My Lord.
Southerners don't
do well up here.
So, what does it mean?
Ask your Maester Luwin.
He's the one studying
books all the time.
I did ask him. He'd never
heard of a three-eyed raven.
- Must not mean anything, then
- You're lying.
You might be a little lord,
but don't you call me a liar.
- You know what it means.
- I never said I didn't.
You didn't give me
an honest answer.
That's not the same
as being a liar.
Well, it's not far off.
So, you've been dreaming
of a three-eyed raven again?
In the Godswood,
you told me you didn't dream.
Now who's a liar?
What did you see
in your dream?
Something bad?
Tell me, boy.
I dreamt that the sea
came to Winterfell.
I saw waves crashing
against the gates
and the water came
flowing over the walls...
flooded the castle.
Drowned men
were floating here
in the yard.
Ser Rodrik
was one of them.
The sea is hundreds
of miles away.
I know.
It's just a stupid dream.
I've got to get these
potatoes to the kitchen.
Otherwise they'll put me
in chains again.
Osha.
The three-eyed raven,
what do they say about it
north of the wall?
They say all sorts of crazy
things north of the wall.
- There.
- Where?
On that Mountain.
I don't see very well.
A fire.
There's a fire.
The people sitting around it have
better eyes than yours or mine.
When they see us coming,
that fire becomes a signal.
Gives Mance Rayder plenty of time.
to throw a party in our honor.
How many wildlings
have joined him?
From what we can tell,
all of them.
Mance has gathered them all
like deer against the wolves.
They're almost ready
to make their move.
Where?
Somewhere safe.
Somewhere south.
Can't just march
into their midst.
And we can't wait for them
here with nothing but a pile
of stones to protect us.
You saying we should
fall back to the Wall?
Mance was one of us once.
Now he's one of them.
He's gonna teach them
our way of doing things.
They'll hit us in force.
And they won't run away
when we hit back.
They're gonna be more
organized than before,
more disciplined
more like us.
So we need to be
more like them,
do things their way.
Sneak in, kill Mance,
and scatter them
to the winds
before they can march
on the Wall.
And to do that...
We need to get rid
of those lookouts.
It's not a job
for 400 men.
I need to move fast
and silent.
Harker, Stonesnake,
Borba.
Lord Commander, I'd like
to join Lord Qhorin.
I've been called
lots of things,
but that might be
my first Lord Qhorin.
You're a steward,
Snow, not a ranger.
I've fought
and killed a Wight.
How many rangers
can say that?
He's the one?
Aye.
You killed a Wight.
You also let an old man
beat you bloody
and take your sword.
Craster?
In the boy's defense,
that's a tough old goat.
I could take up Jon's duties
while he's gone, My Lord.
It would be no trouble.
Well, I hope you make
a better ranger
than you do a steward.
Go on.
So, tell me,
how long has your manservant
been in love with you?
He's not my manservant
and he's not in love with me.
He's my advisor,
my friend.
Unlikely.
I can almost always tell
what a man wants.
And what about
what a woman wants?
Much more complicated.
You, for example,
what do you want?
To cross the Narrow Sea
and take back the Iron Throne.
Why?
Because I promised
my Khalasar I'd protect them
and find them a safe home.
You want to conquer
the Seven Kingdoms?
I want them because
they're mine by right.
The Iron Throne is mine
and I will take it.
Ah, a conqueror.
And how did you get
all of this?
- Did someone give it to you?
- No.
I come from nothing.
I hit the docks
like a piece of cargo,
except someone normally
cares what happens to cargo.
So you wanted more than
you had and you took it.
You're a conqueror, too.
you're just less ambitious.
Mmm.
What do you want,
Xaro Zhoan Daxos?
At the gates of the city,
you bled for me.
Why?
I will show you why.
The door and the vault
is made of Valyrian stone.
The hardest steel
does not make a mark.
I offered the greatest
locksmiths in Qarth
their weight in gold
if they could break into it.
I made the same offer
to the greatest thieves.
They all went home
empty-handed.
The only thing that
can open this door
is this key.
And behind the door?
And it can all be mine?
All?
Let us say half.
More than enough to buy
horses, ships, armies--
enough to go home.
All I have to do?
Is marry me.
That was a romantic proposal.
I've already married
once for love,
but the Gods
stole her from me.
I come from nothing.
My mother and father
never owned a pair of shoes.
But marry me and I will
give you the Seven Kingdoms
and our children will be
Princes and Princesses.
See?
I have more ambition
than you thought.
The time is right,
Daenerys Targaryen,
first of your name.
Robert Baratheon
is dead.
If you cross the sea
with an army you bought--
The Seven Kingdoms are
at war with one another.
Four false kings
destroying the country.
To win Westeros, you need
support from Westeros.
The usurper is dead.
The Starks fight
the Lannisters,
and Baratheons
fight each other.
According to
your new friend
who earned your trust
by cutting his hand?
The time to strike is now. We need
to find ships and an army
or we'll spend the rest
of our lives rotting away
at the edge of the world.
Rich men do not become rich
by giving more than they get.
They'll give you ships and soldiers
and they'll own you forever.
Moving carefully is the hard way,
but it's the right way.
And if I'd listened
to that advice
outside the gates of Qarth,
we'd all be dead by now.
I know the opportunity before you
seems like the last you'll ever have,
but you must--
Do not speak to me
like I'm a child.
- I only want--
- What do you want?
Tell me.
To see you
on the Iron Throne.
- Why?
- You have a good claim.
A title.
A birthright.
But you have something
more than that.
You may cover it up and deny it,
but you have a gentle heart.
You would not only
be respected and feared,
you would be loved.
Someone who can rule
and should rule.
Centuries come and go
without a person like that
coming into the world.
There are times
when I look at you
and still can't
believe you're real.
So what would you
have me do as my advisor?
Make your own way.
Find your own ship.
You only need one.
The allies we need
are in Westeros, not Qarth.
And how do I get
the ship?
I'll find it for you.
A sound ship
with a good captain.
I look forward
to meeting him.
Khaleesi.
You should stand
sideface.
Sideface?
Sideways.
- Why?
- Smaller target.
Am I fighting someone?
You're practicing
for a fight.
You should practice right.
Guards!
- Help.
- Did you see anything?
Go up there. Go and see where
he fell from.
Go up the back.
That is strange.
Move away.
Stand back.
He's dead.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==